- 谁负责现场调查? - Massey和Crutchfield
- Who's got the scene? - Massey and Crutchfield are working it
Norris正赶去停尸房 他会在那儿检查尸体
Norris is on his way to the morgue. He'll beat the bodies there.
- 鉴证科的人在哪? - 氧气够他用的吗?
- How about the crime lab? - Can he get enough oxygen here?
我们在给他做全面治疗呢 老大
He's getting the full treatment, boss.
你会好起来的
???
情况不错
We're good there.
目前为止只有一名目击证人
Just one witness so far.
也就是说他所能提供的最多就是 BNBG (白人受害人常用的说辞 大个子黑人 大枪)
You know what that means. Right now it's all BNBG.
这可是Andy Kraw的大冒险经历呢
It's Andy Kraw's big adventure.
市长办公室已经打来两次电话 对此君表示极度关心
Mayor's office already called twice, worried sick about the man.
有这等事?
You're kidding me.
这位老兄所说的话将会 为某人的竞选赢得大量选票呢
That's a whole lotta campaign contributions sitting on the back of that ambo.
现场调查结果是什么?
So what's the scene say?
两名射击者 散弹枪 半自动
Two shooters. Shotgun, semiauto.
一名死者是西区的一名打手 没有任何案底
One vic is a West Side soldier with a pretty healthy sheet
另一名是Daniel所监听的案子中的主角
the other is a major player in Daniel's wiretap case.
看来是一次与毒品有关的刺杀
So a hit. Drug related.
一名大地产开发商牵扯在里面?
With a big time developer in the middle?
那个大开发商是谁?
What's the fit?
第二名死者 Russell Bell
Second vic, Russell Bell
是这家公司的业主及合作开发商
owner and co-developer of this here.
还有城里的其他房地产
And other downtown real estate.
这人拥有很多财产 曾经拥有
Well propertied man, he was.
但你们都应该知道Russell Bell 曾经是一名重大贩毒罪犯
But you were aware that Russell Bell was regarded as a major narcotic violator.
要不然你说他哪来的钱啊?
Well, how do you think he made his money?
我没有问他们
I didn't inquire.
这么说你一直没看见那两个枪手长什么样?
so, You never got a look at either of the gunmen.
我说过了 我只看到他们中的一个人
I told you. I saw only the one of them.
他是个黑人 我觉得他个儿挺高大的
He was black big, I thought,
拿着一枝巨大的武器
with a large weapon.
BNBG
BNBG.
那是大个儿黑鬼和大枝枪的缩写
Big negro, big gun.
楼上还有两个这样的
Two more like it upstairs.
知道了
Yeah.
让弹道专家做加急对比
Have ballistics rush comparisons.
所有过去六个月里与毒品有关的案子
Drug-relateds for the last six months.
我已经抓到他的马脚了 Bunk
I caught him, Bunk.
在窃听线上 我已经抓到他的马脚了
On the wire. I caught him.
而他还他妈的蒙在鼓里呢
He doesn't fuckin'know it.
火线重案组 第三季 第12集
the.wire.s03e12
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
“我们为那个谎言而战” -- Slim Charles
拳击赛 太好了
Boxing, yeah.
我知道你爱看这个
I know you loved that.
我讨厌拳击 我可讨厌看了
Ugh, I hated it. I hated watching it.
是啊 我知道的 你一切都挺好的吧?
Yeah, I know you did. So you're doing good, huh?
平平淡淡 还好了
Day to day, I am.
我是想着 也许...
'Cause I was thinking maybe...
我为你骄傲 Dennis 好好保重
I'm proud of you, Dennis. Be well.
把门他妈的给我关上
Shut that fuckin'door.
哥们儿 去它的 这事我已经准备好了
Man, fuck it. I'm ready for this shit.
这些黑鬼头们在藐视我们 你没看出来么?
These niggers are snappin'on us. You see?
你相信那些鬼话么?
Do you believe this fucking shit? ???
老Barksdale在的时候 像这种烂事根本就不会发生
Some shit like this woulda never happened with the old Barksdale.
哎 Slim 哥们儿 下令吧 他奶奶地你就下个令吧
Yo, Slim, man. Say the motherfuckin'word.
就要开战了
Shit is on.
怎么样 B?
'Sup, B?
你还好么?
You a'ight?
我们一定回击那个鸟人 毫无疑问的
We gonna bounce back on the motherfucker, no question.
回击谁?
Bounce back on who?
Marlo 老大 看着吧 他就要被放倒了
Marlo, boss. Oh, he gonna fall.
Marlo么 Marlo跟这事没瓜葛
Marlo, Marlo ain't got shit to do with it.
Marlo没法把String弄成那样
Marlo couldn't get String like that.
String是因为别的原因死的
String died'cause of some other shit.
什么?
What?
他是因为别的原因死的 黑小子
He died because of some other shit, nigger.
我试过想搞定的 但没成功
I couldn't fix it. I tried.
String那小子是对的 兄弟
That nigger String was right about this shit, man.
他说的是对的 操它妈的Marlo
That nigger was right. Fuck Marlo.
操它妈的这场鸟战争
Fuck this fucking war.
所有这些争端只不过是为了一两个鸟街角
All this beef over a couple of fuckin'corners.
这会儿咱也甭管是谁对谁做了什么
Don't matter who did what to who at this point.
事实就是 我们已经开战了 现在没得回头了
Fact is, we went to war and now there ain't no going back.
管它妈的这仗是为什么而打的
I mean, shit it's what war is, you know.
只要你参加了 你就在里头了
Once you in it, you in it.
如果那是一个谎言 那我们就为那个谎言而战
If it's a lie then we fight on that lie
但我们得战斗下去
but we gotta fight.
这是从他口袋里找到的
Got this out of his pocket.
不知道是什么东西
I got no idea.
这是手机里的芯片
It's a cell chip from a phone.
哦
oh.
你还找到别的什么东西了?
What elsedid you get off him?
200块现金 一套钥匙 驾照
200 cash, set of keys, license.
驾照上地址是President街么?
President Street address?
我让Landsman帮我 争取到一张那个地方的搜查令
I got Landsman bangin'out a warrant for the place.
把见鬼的政治先放一边
Fuck the politics for a minute.
万一那个人是对的怎么办?
What if the man happens to be right?
毒品合法化?
Legalizing drugs?
他的辖区里犯罪率下降了
Crime is down in his district
而且那边的居民对此都能接受
and people on that side of town, they're okay with it.
如果你不存在 这里会怎么样?
Look, if you don't exist, what happens here?
如果Tommy Carcetti没有插手这件事儿 会有什么样的情况出现?
If there's no Tommy Carcetti in this thing, what's likely to happen?
市长和Burrell 他们把这事压下来了
The mayor and Burrell, they shut this thing down.
我估计市长是想找个途径把这事压下来 万一这事被公开了
I figure the Mayor's trying to find a way to shuit down to make it look like
让它看起来好象是一次警方策划的行动
it was an enforcement plan in case it goes public
否则的话 他早就采取行动终止它了
otherwise he'd have moved to end it already.
有道理 但不管怎么样
Makes sense. But no matter what
Colvin的小实验结束了
Colvin's little experiment is finished.
拜托 Tommy
Come on, Tommy.
他们发给你一手包赢的牌 而你却表现得好象忘记该怎么玩了
They dealt you a winning hand and you're acting like you forgot how to play.
市长先生 毒品要合法化 我部门的人无法接受
Mr. Mayor, call it legalization and my office can't live with it.
同意 没人能够
Agreed. No one can.
但有减低伤害的效果
But harm reduction.
犯罪率降低的数据可以提供出来增加说服力
That could sell provided there's a reduction in the crime rate.
减低伤害 听起来不错嘛
Harm reduction. Sounds good. ??
Steven 假如我们能够向公众说
Steven, what if we were able to suggest
限制我们维持街道治安的警力是为了
limiting our street level enforcement
把我们的资源集中起来打击高层的毒枭们
we were concentrating our resources on high-level traffickers.
这样能玩得转么?
How would that play?
如果我能拿得出那种案子来证明的话 没准可以行得通
Well, if I could show off that kind of casework, yeah, maybe.
但他们做街面犯罪这么长时间了
But they've been doing street rips for so long now
恐怕所谓高层并不存在
I don't think a high level exists.
那假如我们能说 在自由区里不允许大毒枭涉足
What if we were able to say that no major traffickers were allowed in the free zone...
所有重大...
that all major...
所有重大毒品犯依然是被针对的目标
That the major violators were still being targeted, huh?
你是说给那些区域设定 某种入驻的尺度标准么?
Are you suggesting some kind of admissions criteria for the zones?
- 这怎么样才能行得通? - 我不知道能不能行得通
- How would that work? - I don't know that it would.
我所说的只是为了便于公众的理解
I'm just saying that for the sake of public perception.
你们都动动脑子啊 一起帮我想办法把这事给摆平了
Come on, people, work with me on this thing.
糟透了 你说是吧?
Fucked up, ain't it?
Marlo得付出代价 他跟他的那伙人
Marlo need to get his ass dropped, him and all his crew.
他们会垮的 小子 走着瞧吧
They gonna fall. You'll see.
好吧 有消息告诉我
All right, let me know.
这反正就是窃听线上所说的了
That's the word on the wire, anyway.
所有提到的这事的 都把它归结到 Marlo Stanfield的团伙
Every mention puts it on Marlo Stanfield's crew
也就是说战争将要扩大了 毫无疑问
which means the war's gonna ratchet up, no question.
Jimmy哪儿去了?
Where's Jimmy?
他跟Bunk Moreland 去搜Stringer在城里的窝点
He went with Bunk Moreland to rifle Stringer's spot downtown.
他对这事反应如何?
How'd he take it?
Stringer就好象是他死去的亲人一样
Like Stringer was kin.
- 喂? - 小毛头
- Yeah? - Bushy Top
- 你得避开人跟我说话 - 嗨 什么事 警长?
- need to pull your coat up.  - Hey, what's up, Major?
我有些东西给你们
I got somethin'for y'all.
一个小时后在Mount Vernon广场见
Mount Vernon Square in about an hour.
一会儿见
I'm there.
这是Stringer住的地方?
This is Stringer's?
可不
Yeah.
我追查的到底是个什么样的人啊?
Who in fuck was I chasing?
(书名“国富论”) (这是一本政治经济学经典著作)
做过的事已经做了
What's done is done.
同性恋帮匪 少来了
Gay ass gangsters. Please.
我能忍多久算多久
I took it for as long as I could.
走吧 兄弟
Let's go, man.
我们走
Let's go.
这是你的地盘
It being your town,
我相信你能妥当处理
I trust you to do it proper.
你今天休息吗 头儿?
You off today, boss?
这段时间每天都休息
Every day, at this point.
我在报告会上 把我做的那个小实验告诉了他们
I told 'em over at COMSTAT about my little experiment.
老大们听了后都抓狂了是吧?
Bosses went crazy, huh?
别提了 这才是我找你的原因
Anyway, that's why I called you.
为了你的那位Barksdale老兄 一场战争已经酝酿起来了
That there is a wartime lay-up for your man Barksdale.
我的线报告诉我 这人在那里 大多数时间都有一大帮打手跟着?
My sources tell me the man's there most of the time with a lot of muscle?
短管枪 半自动枪 冲锋手枪
sawed-offs, semiautos, Mac-11s.
如果你能逮个正着 就能得到许多好东西
Whole lot of good shit if you hit it right.
- 这个情报太强大了 - 屁事一桩
- That's a hell of a tip. - Shit.
你手里握着的可能是作为警察
That right there might be the last bit of
在这一漫长且传奇的职业生涯中的最后一点功绩了
police work in a long and storied career.
我们再联络吧 小毛头
I'll talk to you, Bushy Top.
哪一个是拳王阿里?
Which one is Ali?
穿白短裤的那个 小鬼
In the white trunks, boy.
- 靠 他看起来好年轻 - 他当年是年轻
- Damn, he look young. - He was.
这是跟Patterson的那场拳赛 传统打法
This the Patterson fight right here. Old school.
Patterson是谁? 他真软蛋
Who Patterson? He soft.
阿里打得他抬不起头
Ali whippin'his ass.
他也曾经是个冠军
He was a champ too.
听着 任何能在拳击台上 坚持到最后仍然不倒的男人
Look, any man still standing at the end of a round
你都不能说他是软蛋 这是规矩 知道没?
you can't call him soft. That's a rule, all right?
在Stringer城里公寓里找到的
From Stringer's place downtown.
B与B什么的 大学文件 地产类的东西
B and B shit, college papers, real estate stuff.
那地方没有电话分机 只有这些
There's no phone extension in the place, just these.
手机芯片 大概有100个
Cell phone chips. 'Bout 100 of them.
这就是为什么他没有 接我们Bernard老兄的任何电话
So that's why he wasn't taking any phones from our man Bernard, huh?
Stringer有他自己的电话 他每换一个芯片就可以换一个电话号码
Stringer had his own phone he just changed the number every time he changed the chip.
Shamrock估计也是一样 不管他用什么电话打给Bell
Shamrock too, probably, with whatever phone he used to call Bell.
挺谨慎的人
Cautious man.
是也不是
Yes and no.
看这儿 全是不同的生产厂家
Have a look in here. All different manufacturers.
谢谢你
Thank you.
在Stringer Bell被杀之前
Before Stringer Bell got aced
他想尽方法让他的好朋友 Avon Barksdale加入其中
he went out of his way to put in his good friend Avon Barksdale.
那是Barksdale的一个藏身所
That's a Barksdale safe house.
你从哪搞来这个的?
Where'd you get this?
Colvin给的
Colvin.
打去西区的电话
Calls to the Western.
Daniels上哪儿去了?
Where's Daniels?
他去参加市里的一个活动 为了支持他老婆
He's got this thing downtown. It's for his wife.
你应该跟他联络
You should raise him.
这还不足以给Stringer立案
It's not enough to make up for Stringer.
目前来讲足矣
It'll do for now.
因为那些周围的邻里及本区的居民
Because the neighborhoods and the residents
是我们市里最为贫困的
in this district are among the poorest in our city.
也正是这些居民
And it is these residents
最需要一个强有力的声音 在市政厅里为他们说话
who most need a strong voice at City Hall.
是时候做出转变了
Time has come for a change.
而我相信我可以带来这个转变
And I believe I can bring about that change
为新十一区提供一个强大的声音
by providing a strong voice for the new 11th District
如果你能给我这个荣耀
if you will do me the honor...
这挺酷的 想想吧 警督的老婆参加竞选哦
It's kind of cool, the lieutenant's wife running for office, you know.
正如你刚才所听到的
Well, as you just heard,
西巴尔的摩市议会的女子 Eunetta Perkins
West Baltimore City Council woman Eunetta Perkins
将要忙于下年九月的民主党最终选举
is going to have her hands full in next September's Democratic finals.
Stringer Bell 靠
Stringer Bell. Damn.
谁能搞得定他啊 我是说 如果不是由你们来动手的话
Who could have got to him? I mean, if it wasn't y'all on it.
你知道 Avon会把一切都怪罪到你头上的 是吧?
You know Avon's gonna put it on you, right?
切 他什么把柄也找不到 我才不担心呢
Shit, let him take it on my jacket. Don't make me no never mind.
我想这大概是那种所谓的巧妙难题吧
I'm thinkin'it might be what you call one of them good problems.
妙啊
Yeah.
我听说Colvin在城里惹上大麻烦了
I heard Colvin's in deep shit downtown.
看看这边这个吧
Looking at this right here
惹上麻烦的可能不止是他一个人
he might not be the only one.
如果有什么情况 用对讲机通知我
Anything comes up, I'm on the radio.
哥们儿 哥们儿 哥们儿
My man, my man, my man.
哎 能给我五块钱吗? 我需要五块钱去搭公车
Yo, you think I could get like $5? I need like $5 to get on the bus.
- 你看着我像游客么? - 大哥 我对天发誓
- I look like a tourist to you? - Man, I swear to God.
穿成那样 走在光天化日下的毒品市场里
Lookin'like that walking into an open-air drug market
我凭什么相信你需要 拿我的五块钱去搭公车呢?
why the hell would I think you'll spend my $5 on bus fare?
妈的 因为我已经把钱都用来买提神丸了
Shit,'cause I already got my blast, man.
大杀器 大杀器
WMD, WMD.
(Cheryl来电)
整一晚上
All night
你喝酒怎么好像不要命一样
you been drinking like your ass is candy.
真是丢人啊
That's shameful shit.
点12弄出来的南瓜大的枪洞
12-gauge pumpkin balls.
上一回我看到这样的架式 是Pimlico的双尸案
Last time I saw that kind of load was the Pimlico double
我就他妈的知道这王八蛋有份在里头搅和
and I fuckin'know that motherfucker was in the middle of that mess.
以我知 你的那个小子
And if I remember your boy
他对Barksdale那伙人根本没有爱心
he had no love for the Barksdale people.
处决手法 这不像是Omar Little的风格
Execution style, that don't play like Omar Little.
再有 我们窃听线上听到的传言 都说是Marlo的人做掉了Stringer
Besides, the word on our wire is that Marlo's people did Stringer.
Marlo Stanfield?
他显然是权力继承人
The heir apparent.
这城市要变成地狱了
This city's going to hell, man.
我们要赶在新年之前 把这超过300单的谋杀案处理掉
We're gonna push past 300 murders before New Year's.
这事搞不定了
Shit is fucked.
喂 Cheryl你好
Oh, hey, Cheryl.
没有? 我想她可能是去接一个囚犯了
No? My guess is she's, uh, picking up a prisoner.
对 我跟她大概十分钟前通过话
Yeah, I spoke to her about ten minutes ago.
对 他们会要你把所有东西拿出来检查
Yeah, well, they make you check your stuff.
手机啊 钱啊 武器啊
Cell phone, money, weapon.
她见到留言会回你电话的
Well, she'll call when she gets the message.
不客气
Not at all.
我还得要喝多些酒 Jimmy
I need more, Jimmy.
再多些!
More?
王八蛋
Motherfucker.
我累了 Bunk
I'm tired, Bunk.
咱走吧
Let's go.
我听说领导们会面了
I heard the vanguard met.
听说他们投票决定 搞一个民众评议板 看大家的意见如何
Heard they voted to have a civilian review board look at it.
不是所有人都反对你的做法
It wasn't unanimous.
况且还有人在那儿为你说话
And there were people there speaking for you.
我也听说了
I heard that too.
那么十个黑人官员中有六个
So six out of ten black officers
认为我是个混蛋种族歧视者
think I'm just an asshole racist.
从另一个角度来看
On the other hand
十个人里有四个认为你就是一混蛋
four out of ten think you're just an asshole.
这是一个行政指控
It's an administrative charge.
如果你愿意 你可以据理力争赢回来
You can fight it and win if you want.
没能以正确的方式表明我的警察身份
Failure to properly identify myself as a police officer.
事实上 这听起来就好象 我的大部分职业生涯里都是有罪的
Sounds like what I was guilty of most of my career, actually.
我不确定警察是不是我该做的行当
I'm not sure I was supposed to be a police.
不太像是
Not really.
那你本该做什么呢?
What were ya supposed to be, huh?
嗯?
mm?
（Wheeler大街228号)
这是Colvin警长的线人提供的?
This is from Major Colvin's CI?
有确凿证明么?
What's the corroboration?
知情人说Barksdale有一所临水公寓 冠的是他自己的名字
Well, the source knew that Barksdale had a waterfront condo in his own name
给出了准确的位置 还有冠名信息以及过户契约
gave the accurate location, and title info down to deed of transfer.
嗯 很不错 但这些只能证明到他所做的那些合法的事情
Well, that's good, but it puts him on the legitimate side of things.
还有什么进一步的证据 可以证明他那些非法活动么?
What corroboration is there for illegal activities?
抱歉 我来晚了 我顺路去见了一朋友
Sorry I'm late. I had to stop in at a friend.
知情人说Barksdale 上个月被枪射伤了肩膀
The source knew that Barksdale was shot last month wounded in the shoulder.
- 急诊室? - 不 没有有医院报告
- Emergency room? - No, no hospital reports.
我们得有更多的证据
We're gonna need better.
要么让Colvin再去找那个线人了解多些情况
Either Colvin goes back to the CI
要么我们就在这个地址守一段时间
or we sit on this address for a while.
- 我们拭目以待 - 这么着的话 去他的吧
- we can see. - Well, fuck it, then.
我们干脆给出线人的名字 直接让他出来做证
Let's name the source. Put him right in the affidavit.
- 这得由Colvin决定 对不对? - 是Stringer Bell
- It's Colvin's call, isn't it? - It's Stringer Bell.
Lester从打过的号码上推断出来
Lester figured it out from the DNRs.
Bell在出卖Barksdale?
Bell was snitching out Barksdale.
你能肯定是这样么?
You're sure of this?
也许这就是他被谋杀的原因 窃听线上有什么收获?
Maybe that explains the murder. What's in the wire?
有些人在说这是Marlo的人做的
Loose talk about how it was Marlo's people
- 但都只是谣传而已 - Bell这一死
- but nothing past rumor. - With Bell gone,
Barksdale可能不得不屈尊亲躬 那些日常管理事务
Barksdale might have to come down a notch to oversee the day to day,
而这可能会促使他去联系 一些被我们窃听的手机的持有者
and maybe that puts him in contact with some of our monitored cell phones.
如果他像Stringer那样谨慎 可能他不会这么做
If he's as cautious as Stringer, maybe not.
我估计Barksdale压根儿就不用手机
My guess is Barksdale never touches a cell phone.
安全屋很有可能是我们最佳的取证所在
Safe house might be our best shot.
好的
All right.
我们要守着窃听线直到这些手机失效为止
We stay on the wires until this batch of burners goes dead,
希望能抓到Barksdale
hoping we have Barksdale
同时 我们拿上安全屋的搜查令 在那儿等着他
but meanwhile, we get a warrant for that safe house and wait on him there.
谢谢你昨晚帮我打掩护
Thanks for the cover last night.
Russell Bell 又名Stringer 因亡撤案
我是重大案件科的Greggs 哪位是当值领导?
This is Greggs, Major Case Unit. Who's the shift leader?
我的老天爷啊
Holy Christ.
- 局长 他们到处都是 - 知道了
- They're all over it, Commissioner. - Right.
是Foxtrot打来的
That was Foxtrot.
摄像机已经找到了我们的那一小堆屎
The cameras have found our little shit pile.
你那该死的议员 可享受到他的甜蜜时光了吧?
Your fuckin'councilman took his sweet time, didn't he?
每个人都是批评家
Everyone's a critic.
如果这事躲不过去 你打算改做哪一行呢?
If this doesn't go, what line of work are you gonna try next?
我们现在在西巴尔的摩
We're here in West Baltimore...
一个多月以来 来自巴尔的摩西区的警察...
For more than a month, police from Baltimore's Western District.
这样的发展状况简直令人无法忍受
It's just an outrageous development.
这是我从没想过会见到的事情 无论是这里还是在别的辖区
It's something I never thought I'd see from this or any other administration.
老实说 这是我们需要对这个城市的 管理层做出改变的其中一个原因
Frankly, this is one of the reasons we need a change in leadership in this city.
市长知道这事么? 局长知道么?
Did the Mayor know? What about the Police Commissione?
这些问题要去问市长和警察局长
These are questions for the Mayor and Police Commissioner.
这些是犯罪与安全事务的中心议题
These are central issues of crime and safety.
Royce政府辖区纯粹就是破产了
The Royce administration is simply bankrupt.
你下个月还会竞选市长么?
You still gonna announce for mayor next month?
我本来想等一等的 但今天站在这里看着这一切
I was gonna wait, but standing here today looking at this..
我觉得自己除了立刻参选之外 没有别的选择了
I can't see I can do anything but put it out there right now.
我所能告诉你的就是 四个多星期以来
All I can tell you is that for more than four weeks now
巴尔的摩警察局拱手
the Baltimore Police Department surrendered
将警方辖区让出来做毒品交易
portions of the police district to the drug trade
把议会蒙在鼓里
and the Council was not informed.
我真蠢
Fuck me.
一个星期前我就已经 他妈的搞到这个故事题材了
I fuckin' had this story all to myself a week ago.
警察们数星期来一直视而不见...
Police officers for weeks have turned a blind eye...
我之前他妈的是怎么想的啊?
What the fuck was I thinking?
...显然认可了开放式的毒品市场
.. apparently sanctioning open-air drug markets.
- 请回避一下 - 在有警察们身着警服站在一旁的...
- 'Scuse us. - While uniformed police stood by...
...所谓的自由区里 毒品贩子们常规地进行着他们的交易
... in the so called free zones, drug dealers routinely ply their trade.
市长先生 Burrell局长来了
Mr. Mayor, Commissioner Burrell is here.
告诉局长 市长很快就会接见他
Tell the Commissioner the Mayor will be with him shortly.
而小孩子们独自在街上跑来跑去
And young children run the streets alone.
在这个被称为Hamsterdam的地段上
The inhabitants of what has come to be known
当地的居民们面对镜头几乎无话可说
as Hampsterdam have little to say for the camera.
但是五频道已经知道 警察局...
But channel 5 has learned that the police were...
- 喂 - 你看到什么了?
- Yeah? - What are you seein'?
几个人进进出出 但没有Barksdale的踪影
Coupla people in and out. No sign of Barksdale, though.
- 我这边也没动静 - 明白
- It's quiet here too.  - Okay.
要去看下后面
Need to look at the back.
我们的老朋友Carcetti 会拿这事大作文章的
Our friend Carcetti's gonna run wild with this.
而从我们所听到的来看 Gray将会跟他一起参选
And from the sound of things, Gray is gonna run with him.
Tony Gray以为他能利用这次事件坐上我的位置
Tony Gray thinks he's gonna get my chair behind this bullshit
我们要把你抛出去当挡箭牌了 Ervin 这事你自己担待着吧
We're throwin'you out of the boat, Ervin. This shit is on you alone.
没这样做的必要
Not necessarily.
因为我将会说出我们为了要 顶住保持低犯罪率的压力
Not if I talk about how we were under pressure to keep the crime down
一个辖区接一个辖区地做假数据
to juke the stats district by district...
不准你这么说
You never said that.
还会说出Colvin在压力之下无计可施
About how Colvin under pressure, lost his way
- 说出我是怎么样在几个星期以前来找你... - 是前天才对
- about how I came to you weeks ago... - a Days ago.
几星期前就告诉你他做了些什么 并且向你保证
Weeks ago to tell you what he had done and to assure you that
我们已经掌控了事态
we were on top of the situation
Colvin将被解职而他的计划将会流产
that Colvin would be relieved and his plan aborted.
你这满口谎言的混帐东西
You lyin'motherfucker.
但你听说Colvin辖区内的重罪率有所下降
But you heard about the drop in Colvin's felony rate
你就把我打发走
and you sent me packing.
带着你的解放派行善人的面孔
Brought in your liberal-ass do-gooders
当真考虑起这狗屁主意
to seriously consider this horseshit
而Colvin的错越犯越犯大
while Colvin's mistake grew and grew.
我的手脚被绑住了 市长先生
My hands were tied, Mr. Mayor
我的部门失败了
my department thwarted.
我则是操蛋政客手中的棋子
I was a prisoner of the goddamn politicians.
或者呢...
Or...
我现在就离开你的办公室 并愿意隐藏大部分这些事实不说
I leave your office right now willing to say a lot less than that.
尽我所能地把责任都推到 疯子Bunny Colvin身上去
I put what I can on crazy-ass Bunny Colvin
由我来挡所有的炮火
and I take the hit.
如果Carcetti或者Gray主持听证会
And if Carcetti or Gray holds hearings
我会是他们跟你们之间的那堵缓冲墙
I'm the wall between them and you.
这样的话
In which case,
你要让我继续在警察局长的位置上 呆足五年的任期
I am your commissioner for the full five-year term.
一分部呼叫二分部
Unit one to unit two.
二分部待命中
Unit two standing by.
交易成功
Deal's made.
二分部呼叫三支队 进发去Winchester之家
Unit two to sector three, move on the Winchester Homes.
好的 我们上路了
Ten-four. We're moving.
二分部呼叫二支队 进发到Koppers发电厂
Unit two to sector two. Move on the Koppers plant.
收到
Roger that.
该我们上了 先生们
Over the top, gentlemen.
也该他妈的是时候了
'Bout fucking time.
嗨 哥们儿 我们要是 再不补仓的话就要没货了
Yo, man. We gonna run out if we don't got no re-up.
- Tuckie哪儿去了? - 我不知道
- Where Tuckie at? - I don't know.
- 哎 Tuckie在哪儿呢? - 他闪人了
- Yo, where Tuckie at, man? - He rolled out.
- 啊? - 他说警察来了
- huh? - He said the police comin'.
- 啊哦 - 他们来了 快闪
- D'oh. - Here they come. Let's roll.
站在那儿别跑 穿白夹克的!
Hold it right there, white jacket!
放开我
Get the fuck off me!
站住! 站住!
Stop! Stop!
- 不准动 - 站那儿别动!
- freeze - Stop right there!
不准动 警察 别动 站那儿别动 不许动
Freeze! Police, don't mov. Hold it right there
好极了 红队 干得好极了
Outstanding, red team. Oustanding.
值得奖给你们一箱啤酒
Give you a case of beer for that one.
小子 这个老黑Stringer Bell呀
Son, this nigga Stringer Bell, man
居然哀求Chris呢 是真的 你想像得出么?
was beggin'Chris, yo, for real. Like know what I mean?
一面掏着他的口袋 一面说他会给我们多少奶酪
Diggin'in his pockets, talkin' 'bout how much cheese he gonna give us,
假如说我们能放他走的话
I mean, if we just let him walk.
我老大Chris大声喝道 "你这贱人 等着拿命来吧 "
My man Chris holler, "Man, bitch, you gonna die. "
这老黑就他妈的跪下来了
This nigga just dropped to his fuckin' knees
好象个小婊子一样 妈的 开始哭起来
like a little cocksucker, man, start cryin'.
那熊样 说他可怜都他妈算抬举他了
That shit was worse than fuckin' pathetic.
哎 那是Marlo
Yo, that's Marlo.
快用手机通话吧
Get on yo'burner, man.
- 有一条线在跟他通话 - 一号么? 在哪
- Got a line on him. - The number one? Where at?
高个儿说 告诉大家都武装起来
Tall man says to tell y'all to soldier up.
- 他们冲着车圈店去了 - 好的
- They up at the rim shop.  - Yeah, all right.
头儿 你还好么?
Boss, you okay?
有什么事?
What you want?
Slim说他们已经盯住Marlo了
Slim said they got their eye on Marlo.
我只是想说 你知道的 所有的小弟们 他们都在等你下令呢
I'm just sayin', you know, all the boys, they all waitin'on you.
行动吧
Go ahead, man.
我随后就到
I'm behind you.
副局长 您还要我们做些什么?
What else you need from us, Deputy?
市政厅要我们用推土车铲平这里
City Hall wants the bulldozers through here
黎明前搞定 再把这地方用围网全部拦起来
at dawnand then fencing all around the site.
温切斯特之家和Koppers发电厂也一样
Winchester Homes and the Koppers plant as well.
我们这就去办
We got it.
明天 那些电视记者来的时候
Come tomorrow, the television reporters
让他们站在这儿什么也没得看
get nothing they can stand in front of.
打扰了 副局长 长官 我们找到一具尸体
'Scuse me, Deputy, sir, we found a body.
有什么伤口吗?
Any trauma?
看不出来 全身都被老鼠咬烂了
Can't tell for sure with all the rat bites.
开辆囚车来把他送去医疗检验总部
Take him to OCME in a jail wagon.
不要让那些操蛋记者看见任何救护车的影子
I don't want the fuckin' reporters seeing any ambos.
靠
Shit.
他刚刚下车 他和另一个人
He just landed. Him plus one.
收到 坐好了
Got it. Sit tight.
加上他们有多少个了?
That makes how many?
包括Barksdale在内 Sydnor已经数到有十个人进去
Including Barksdale, Sydnor counted ten in
有一个正走出来 所以至少有十人
and one comin'out, so that's ten at least.
2301呼叫调度中心
2301 to KGA.
2301请说
Go ahead, 2301.
我们需要快速反应小组与我们在此处会合 进行搜查和拘捕
We need QRT to meet us at our 20 for a search and seizure.
该处有多名疑犯并可能携有自动类武器
Location has multiple suspects and may contain automatic weapons.
收到
Ten-four.
传得真快啊
Word travels fast, huh?
靠
Shit.
Burrell今早亲自打电话给Johns Hopkins
Burrell called Johns Hopkins personally this morning.
诋毁你的名声
Dragged your name into the gutter.
Johns Hopkins不想搞臭自己
Johns Hopkins doesn't need the notoriety.
一所著名的研究大学的学院总长官
The chief academic officer of a major research university
不想在他就任期间 见到一些新招聘的人乱定规矩
doesn't want to hear that some new hire makes up the rules as he goes along.
- 我是Colvin - 警长 你排在头一个
- Yeah, Colvin. mm. - Yeah, Major, you're on first.
明天的报告会
COMSTAT tomorrow.
我准备好了
I'm up.
你们都守着一个门?
Y'all taking a door?
战术小组呢?
Where's tactical?
我叫来了快速反应小组
I called for QRT.
你没听说么?
You ain't heard?
他们今晚在忙着把Colvin 惹上麻烦的那片地方铲平呢
They're a little busy tonight tearin'down Colvin's fuck up.
有那么多事情发生 你还能有我们来帮忙已经算幸运的了
With all that goin'on, you're lucky you even got us.
他这是在整谁呢?
Who he hittin' on this?
Avon Barksdale及其同伙
Avon Barksdale and crew.
我他妈的告诉过你他肯定出狱了 我是不是他妈的告诉过你?
I fuckin' told you he was out. Did i fuckin' tell you?
我早他妈的告诉过她
I fuckin' told her.
超过四个星期以来 巴尔的摩警察局...
For more than four weeks, the Baltimore Police Department...
拱手将警方辖区让给出来做毒品交易
surrendered portions of the police district to the drug trade.
到明天 这件事会传遍全国 华盛顿将做出回应
By tomorrow, the story goes national and Washington reacts.
把最好的问题留着给Tony Gray
Save the best questions for Tony Gray.
他比你更需要披上光环
He needs to shine even more than you.
(议会听证的提问草稿）
我真没想到他会让我们去敲门
I can't believe he wants us to knock.
你现在反正是不能刷枪管了吧
Well, you can' flush guns, now, can you?
我靠 万一他们开门 跟我们撞个正着怎么办?
Well, fuck that. What if they open up on us?
这些家伙在跟另一伙人开战呢
These guys are at war with another crew.
我们要是冲进去 肯定会中招的
We go chargin'in there, chances are we will get lit up.
哎 B哥
Yo, B.
Sham说Charles说 他们仍然在车圈店那儿呢
Sham sayin'that Charles sayin'they still up at the rim shop.
Marlo和他的手下Chris还有Vinson 他们还在吃东西
Marlo, his boy Chris, and Vinson, they still eatin'
但是其他的打手 他们都跑掉了
but the rest of the muscle, they rolled out.
警察
Police.
不
No.
不能对警察用这个
Not the police.
- 缉毒警也在后面呢 - 靠
- Narco's out back too. - Shit.
让我们进去 我们知道你在那儿
Let us in? We know you're in there.
- 死黑鬼 - 我靠
- Fucking nigga. - shit.
- 开门 你他奶奶的鸟人 - 真他妈的要命
- Open the door, you fucking cocksucker - Fucked up, man.
你们都来问我 你们这帮狗杂种们 就不应该在这里搞事
Y'all ask me, y'all ugly ass niggers shouldn't be in here fucking around
还拿着这么些枪啊刀啊的 你们知道我在说什么嘛?
with all these guns and shit, you know what I'm talking about?
开门
Open it.
别磨蹭了 Avon 少来这套 赶紧把这破门给开开
Come on, Avon. Enough with this shit. Open the fucking door.
警察 快他妈的打开门 王八蛋
Open the fucking door, you cocksuckers.
警察
Police
趴地上!
On the floor!
搜查令在此
Search warrant
我没犯法啊
I'm clean, man.
把门他妈的给我打开来
Open the fucking door.
跪下 跪下
Get down.
老老实实对着那儿 Greggs 我去开门
Face that shit tight. Greggs. I'm opening up.
那个是我的
That'd be mine.
事实上 全部都是我的
In fact, all that's mine.
你难道考了法律文凭么?
You got a law degree?
把他带走
Take him.
你已经违反了假释条例 不管有没犯别的什么事都没关系
You fall on the parole violation. No matter whatever else happens
你要坐满七年刑期剩下的每一天 无权上诉
you do every day of what's left of your seven without seeing a jury.
可能还要连带上合谋杀人罪
Maybe even conspiracy to murder.
我们把这案子送到联邦法院
We take this federal,
看能不能给你判个十年至终生监禁没得保释
see if we can get you ten to life...no parole.
随你们便
Whatever.
靠 不管怎么样就只有两天服刑期 你进去的那天
Shit, you only do two days no how. That's the day you go in.
还有你出来的那一天
And the day you come out.
是嘛 喏 这是搜查令
Yeah, well, here's the warrant.
你慢慢看吧
You read it slow.
在那两天之间 这能给你一些事情去好好琢磨
In between them two days, give you something to think on.
(情报来源: Russell Bell 又名Stringer Bell)
靠
Damn.
错过我们的开枪机会了
Missed our shot.
走人吧
Roll, man.
你要是不乖乖地屈服 我对天发誓
You bend over for us, or I swear to God
只要我在位 我就会不留余力地
I will spend what's left of my career
搞臭你辖区里的每一个主管
shitting on every last supervisor in your district.
上至主管指挥官下至小分队长
From shift commanders down to sector sergeants,
让他们一个都别想得到晋升的机会
not one of them will have any rank at all
所以你还是不要跟我们放狗屁的好
if we hear so much as a bark out of you.
听我说 我的手下只是把这事 当做是一次战略调度而已
Look, my people saw this as a tactical deployment only.
这事完全是我一个人的责任
The responsibility is mine alone.
落马的不会只有你一个人
Well, you won't fall alone
除非你愿意完全按我们所要求的方式落马
unless you're willing to fall exactly as we want you to.
报告会后 你去退休服务处递交申请
After COMSTAT, you go to retirement services and drop papers,
以警督的级别离任
going out at a lieutenant's grade
没错 你被降级了 我们不能改变你的退休日期
That's right, you're busted back. We can't take your EOD away
但你不能拿着警长的薪水离任
but you're not going out on a major's pay.
我可以在你们降我的级之前退休
I can retire before you bust me.
我的假期够我完成30年的工龄的了
I got vacation time enough to make my 30.
去你的假期吧
Fuck your vacation time.
你今天就得以低一级别离任
You're out today, at the lower grade.
这样做他妈的是违反合同
That's against the goddamn contract.
你到底明不明白什么叫屈服啊?
What part of bend over didn't you understand?
Avon被关起来了?
Avon locked up?
跟大部分他的手下一起 没错
With most of his muscle, yeah.
这岂不是大好的时机 去把他们的地盘占回来?
Good day to get back out on them corners, ain't it?
赚点钱吧
Make some money.
可不是嘛
You bet.
你所危及的不仅仅是联邦政府 向巴尔的摩警方
It's not just the 17 millions in federal funding
提供的1千7百万元美金资金
for Baltimore law enforcement that you've jeopardized.
在你的运作预算里拿掉另外2亿的联邦款项
Take off another 200 million of federal money in your operating budget
还有另外的7千5百万资本支出
another 75 in capital expenditures,
加上从Annapolis把联邦经费转过来 所花的不知多少百万的过手费
plus untold millions in pass-through federal dollars from Annapolis.
所有都算上 我们这儿讨论的是
All told, we're talking about
巴尔的摩一年要少掉50亿美元的经费
half a billion a year that Baltimore will be doing without.
还没完呢 联邦检察官将会动用执法部门的
Furthermore, the U.S. Attorney here will use all the resources
所有资源去制止和破坏任何尝试
of the Justice Department to interdict and destroy any attempt
去建立一个毒品合法的地理实体的企图
to establish a geographic entity where drugs are legal.
华盛顿应该知道在西巴尔的摩所发生的事情
Washington should know that what happened in West Baltimore
完全不能代表我部门的管理政策
in no way reflects the policies of my administration.
那是一个失常的行为 Talmadge先生
That was an aberration, Mr. Talmadge.
是由一个被误导的警察官员做出来的
The work of one misguided police official.
我们明白你所担心的是什么
We understand your concerns
但对于监管毒品的警官
but for the deputy drug czar
超时工作开车30英里北上去传达那个信息
to take the time out to drive 30 miles north to deliver that message,
几乎完全没有必要
hardly necessary.
放心好了
Rest assured.
你好吗 小G?
What up, G?
那些大孩子们呢?
Where the older ones at?
Marlo的人都逃过去了
Marlo got his package back out.
炒掉Burrell 这些无厘头的事情从他的部门而起
Fire Burrell. This nonsense began in his shop
而他从不知情 把他炒掉 我们再走下一步
without him knowing it. Fire the man and move on.
Odell 我尊重你的意见
Odell, I respect your opinion.
但现在
But right now
Tony Gray和Carcetti在操纵一切
Tony Gray, Carcetti maneuvering
现在不是时候
now is not the time. ??
我们把这首要的事情搞定之后 我会给他的心窝上捅那么一刀
We get past the primary, then I'll drive a stake in his heart.
但现在我需要他保持在原位上 不为别的 只为了
But right now I need him where he is for no other reason than to
为了在那儿承受住这件事情的冲击
well, to take the hit for this thing right here.
不过我要告诉你我的打算
But I tell you what I'm gonna do, though.
我要让你喜欢的那个 11区新来的姑娘披上光环
I'm gonna shine on that new girl you like in the 11th. yeah.
对 我要给她投票 把Eunetta摆脱掉
Give her a spot on the ticket. Cut Eunetta loose.
Eunetta已经享过她的好日子了
Eunetta's had her day.
我看重你站在我这一边的事实 Odell
I respect the fact that you stood by me, Odell.
我看重忠诚
I respect loyalty.
他这么做的时候并没有恰当地 向他的主管官员进行汇报
And did so without properly informing his superior officers
也没有考虑他曾向警队宣誓遵从的犯罪条例
and without regard to the criminal statutes he was sworn to enforce
从而诋毁了他自己和他的部下的声誉
thereby disgracing himself and his command.
你对这件事有任何反驳
Is any of that subject to any contradiction
或者需要做任何辩白么 Colvin警长?
or argument whatsoever, Major Colvin?
没有 长官
No, sir.
没有任何辩白么 Bunny?
No argument at all, Bunny?
没什么可说的吧? 不能对真正的警察说什么
Not much you can say, is there? Not to real police.
- 赶紧完事儿吧 狗娘养... - 你说啥呢 警长?
- Get on with it, motherfu... - 'Scuse me, major?
行政警督在么?
Is the admin lieutenant present?
Colvin警长被解职了
Major Colvin is relieved of duty.
你现在是西区的代理指挥官了
You are now the acting commander of the Western District.
靠 Bernard 我是不是 早告诉过你这些人的事情?
Damn, Bernard, didn't I tell you about these guys?
- 嗨 Bunk - 嗨 Freamon
- Hey, Bunk. - Hey, Freamon.
那是谁啊? Crutchfiel?
Who is that? Crutchfiel?
没啦 是Norris
Naw, Norris.
在监视行动中睡着了
Sleeping on a stakeout.
靠 Bernard 我是不是 早告诉过你这些人的事情?
Damn, Bernard, didn't I tell you about these guys?
没错 我们在窃听线上所听到的人全在那儿了
Yeah, that's everyone we heard on the wire.
McNulty跟Pearlman在那边一号房 过去打个招呼吧
McNulty's over there in number one with Pearlman. Why don't you say hey?
好咧
All right.
你可以说是跟我一起 在外面混的人中最蠢的一个了
You got to be the stupidest motherfucker that I've ever gone out with.
我等不及进监狱了
I can't wait to go to jail.
什么? 你说什么?
What? What you say?
你他妈的说什么呢 Bernard?
What the fuck did you say, Bernard?
嗨 Donald
Hey, Donald.
- 你听过带子上录的了 - 他来找我说
- You heard the tapes. - Look, he came to me and said
如果我们迁到Vincent街去 我们可以卖毒品
we could sell drugs if we move down to Vincent Street
所以我就把我的人迁到那儿去了
and that's where I moved my crew.
而你知道我做的事
And you know I did
因为你就是那个搜出我身上毒品的人
because you the one that popped me with the G-pack
就在我去那个地方的路上的时候 然后你放我走了 记得不?
on my way to the spot, and let me go, remember?
你在Colvin警长的自由区里卖毒品?
You were selling drugs in Major Colvin's free zone?
- 你可以证实么 - 问他 他知道
- You can prove that. - Ask him. He know.
这准定就是勾捕了吧
This must be one of them contrapment things.
- 你是说诱捕吧? - 这小孩说得在理
- You mean entrapment. - Kid's got a point.
19人被从Barksdale抓获拘留
19 in bracelets from Barksdale on down.
对另外8人发了通缉令
Another eight wanted on warrants.
你有什么办法能把你的案子 跟Colvin搞出来的乱摊子挂上勾么?
Any way you can tie your case to this mess with Colvin?
让它看起来好象是他所做的事 导致了你手上的这件案子的发生?
Make it like what he was doing led to your thing?
我看不出有联系
I don't see it.
这个嘛
Well,
不管怎么说 这案子破得好 Daniels警长
it's good work nonetheless, Major Daniels.
半小时前市长办公室打来电话
Call came in from the Mayor's office half hour ago
批准了对你的晋升
approving your promotion.
刚好Colvin离了职 有一个新空缺等着呢
And now with Colvin, there's a new vacancy.
- 我妻子怎么样? - 她怎么了?
- What about my wife? - What about her?
市长那边 Eunetta的席位
The Mayor. Eunetta's seat.
- 市长为什么要... - 大概因为警察工作做得好吧
- Why would the Mayor... - Good police work maybe.
不是每件事都是政治
Not everything is politics.
嘿 我拿两罐 我是西区以前的同仁
Hey, I'll take two. Western alumni.
好的 你拿吧
All right, you got it.
警长
Major.
我听说了
I heard.
你的家人对这事有什么反应?
How's your family take it?
Lolita减肥成功 掉了30磅
Lolita done dropped herself 30 pounds
拿到了她的地产经纪执照
and got herself a real estate license
所以我想她现在 正收拾东西要离开我了
so I guess she's fixin'to leave me.
我只想要你知道
I just wanted you to know
你上次给我的情报破了个大案子
that last tip you gave me was a winner.
嗯 我听说了
Yeah, I heard.
干得漂亮
That's good work.
还有 不知你知不知道 Stringer Bell两天前被杀了
Also, I don't know if you know, Stringer Bell was shot to death two days ago.
所以我
So anyway,
把他的名字写到文件里帮警方结案
I put his name on the paper to tighten the PC.
我想着 管他呢 反正他都死了 对吧?
I figured what the fuck once he's aced, right?
你小子总是走捷径办案子啊
You always did cut them corners, didn't you?
你自己不也是走了点捷径嘛 警长
Seems like you cut a few yourself, Major.
不管这事结果如何 你是好警察
However it ends, you're good police.
我只是做了我所做的
I just did what I did.
感觉挺对劲
It felt right.
我问心无愧
I'm fine with that.
Tony 我的背心哪去了?
Tony, where's my vest, man?
- 谢谢 - 谢了
- Thank you. - Thanks.
我不懂
I don't understand.
喝你的红酒吧
Drink your wine.
你跟我在公众场合出现
You and me in public.
- 但你老婆 - 她没有我也赢了
- But your wife. - She wins without me.
凭着市长投的票 她赢了
On the Mayor's ticket, she wins.
而你当上了警长?
And you make major?
我想她比我任何时候 都更急切地等着这一天的到来
I think she was waiting for this day more than I ever was.
而她现在却不在这里
And now she's not here.
没错
No.
她没在这儿
She's not.
莫名其妙地就来了哈?
From out of nowhere, huh?
莫名其妙就对了
Nowhere is right.
为什么找我?
Why me?
我觉得你的生活不太如意
I guess you don't live right.
- Kari什么东西在响? - 没什么
- Kari, what was that? - Nothing.
- 打破什么了? - 没有啦 妈
- What broke? - Nothing, Mama.
那么...
So...
是的
Yeah.
你就开车过来了
You just drive over here.
对啊
I did.
为什么要在今晚? 发生什么事了?
Why tonight? What happened?
我今晚去我以前的那个区
I was in my old district tonight
我想我以前在那儿一直都感觉挺好的
which is where I used to feel pretty good, I think.
不管怎么说 我那时在那儿 没现在这么大火气
I wasn't so angry when I was there anyway.
我不清楚为什么 可能是有人说了些什么话吧
I don't know, someone said something, I guess
而且 其实也说不通了
and, uhit doesn't make sense.
我想今天我了结了一些事情
I guess I finished something today.
一桩案子?
A case?
不止是案子
More than that.
就好象所有我倒进杯子里的东西 都从底下漏出去了
It's like everything I poured into a glass came out the bottom
而我还在一直地倒啊倒啊
and I just kept on pouring.
就好象那东西穿了底一样
Like the thing had a hole in it, you know.
那些让我适合做这工作的东西
Things that make me right for this job
也许正是让我 不适合做其他任何事情的东西
maybe they're the same things that make me wrong for everything else.
你想进来喝一杯么?
Do you want to come inside for a drink?
今晚不了
Not tonight.
不过如果不是太晚的话 我倒不介意
But if it's not too late, I wouldn't mind
见见你的孩子们
meeting your kids.
Colvin警长误导了他属下的警官
Major Colvin misled his officers.
他们以为他的新方案 是一种战术上的发展
They thought that his initiative was a tactical deployment
用以诱捕麻醉毒品贩子
to entrap narcotics traffickers.
从来没有向任何主管长官
There was no mention whatsoever
提及任何关于这个新方案的事情
of the initiative to any superior officer.
在长达五个星期里
And for five weeks,
所有关于他所做的事情的证据 都巧妙地避过了整个部门职员的耳目
all evidence of what he was doing managed to elude the entire command staff.
你在开玩笑么 局长?
Are you kidding, Commissioner?
我承担全部责任
I take full responsibility
确确实实的 在我首次听说此事的时候
and indeed, after I first learned of the matter
我通知了市长 我们一起立即迅速地采取了行动
I informed the Mayor, and together we moved immediately
解除了Colvin警长的指挥权
to relieve Major Colvin of his command.
让我感到不可思议的是
I'm under the impression that
这个管理机构对于Colvin的 创新方案给予了认真的考虑
this administration gave serious consideration with Colvin's initiative.
没这回事 长官
No, sir.
Colvin警长在一个多星期以前的 一次报告会上
Major Colvin informed you of his effort at a COMSTAT meeting
向你通报了他的作法
more than a week ago.
在那之后他的自由区域存在了足足6天
His free zones stayed up for six days after that.
议员 那是我的责任
That's my responsibility, Councilman.
我们需要那段时间 让重大罪案小组 对一次进行中的调查行动做出总结
We needed the time to conclude an ongoing investigation by the Major Crime Unit,
如果我们立即采取行动的话 一单在窃听中的案子将会被迫中断
a wiretap case  that would have been disrupted had we moved immediately.
正是这样 Royce市长当时 得知有这一未完成的案子的存在
Correct, Mayor Royce was aware of the pending case
所以同意我们延缓对该事件进行反应
and allowed us to delay our response accordingly.
但市长对于Colvin警长的所做所为
But the Mayor was unequivocal
是毫不含糊地持反对态度的
in his opposition to what Major Colvin did.
我们在这里所看到的 恐怕也没有什么复杂的
What we have here, I'm afraid, is nothing more complicated
只不过是一位警察指挥官单枪匹马 在极大的压力之下
than a solitary police commander who, under great pressure
被证实是既无道德原则 也不称职
proved to be amoral, incompetent,
更不适于担当指挥岗位
and unfit for command.
不是这样的
No.
不仅仅是这些
It's about more than that.
这件事更重要的方面不在于 谁知道些什么及何时
This is more important than who knew what when
或者谁倒在了自己的剑下
or who falls on his sword
或者是否有人能利用这一场祸事 来制造一个或两个政治观点
or whether someone can use this disaster to make a political point or two.
- 主席先生... - 我们可以原谅Colvin警长
- Mr. Chairman... - We can forgive Major Colvin
他只是在他的失败与绝望之余 发现自己在纵容一些
who, out of his frustration and despair, found himself condoning something
绝不能够被纵容的事情 我们可以原谅他至此
which can't possibly be condoned. We can do that much.
但是 先生们 我们所不能原谅的是
But, gentlemen, what we can't forgive,
我所从来都不能原谅的
what I can't forgive ever
是我们如何...
is how we...
包括你 我 这个管理机构 我们所有的人
you, me, this administration, all of us
我们如何罔顾西巴尔的摩的那些街区
how we turned away from those streets in West Baltimore.
我们城市那些穷苦而疾病缠身的 低层阶级被困在
The poor, the sick the swollen underclass of our city trapped
这个曾经那么被看重 而今却残骸遍地的街坊里
in the wreckage of neighborhoods which were once so prized.
这些我们未能保卫的
Communities which we've failed to defend,
这些我们出让给恐怖的毒品交易的社区
which we have surrendered to the horrors of the drug trade.
如果说这场混乱对我们作为一个城市 提出了任何要求的话
And if this disaster demands anything of us as a city
它需要我们说 够了
it demands that we say enough.
向令致警察想到要放任自流的 那种绝望说够了
Enough to the despair which makes policemen even think about surrender.
向这街坊邻里没被打救过 或者被救之不及的事实说够了
Enough to the fact that these neighborhoods are not saved or are beyond the saving.
向这个管理机构的优柔寡断 和瞌睡状态说够了
Enough to this administration's indecisiveness and lethargy
还有那些未被收集的垃圾
to the garbage which goes uncollected
那边有许多空置了的排房
the lots and row houses which stay vacant
那些得不到治疗的瘾君子
the addicts who go untreated
那些每天都被拒绝享有经济自由的 工作中的男男女女们
the working men and women who every day are denied a chance at economic freedom.
向那每一天越来越窒息着
Enough to the crime, which every day
我们城市的罪案说够了
chokes more and more of the life from our city.
还有...
And...
事实是 如果我们不承担起责任并站出来
the thing of it is, if we don't take responsibility and step up
不仅仅是为了犯下的错误和失策
not just for the mistakes and the miscues
也无论我们是否将要 为我们的街区赢得这场战役
but for whether or not we're gonna win this battle for our streets
如果不这样做的话
if that doesn't happen
我们将要失去这些街坊 并且最终将永远地 失去这个城市
we're gonna lose these neighborhoods and ultimately this city forever.
如果我们没有勇气和信念
If we don't have the courage and the conviction
去打这场战役 以应有的方式和需要的方式去打
to fight this war they way it should be fought the way it needs to be fought,
使用每一件我们可能集结的武器
using every weapon that we can possibly muster,
如果不是这样的话
if that doesn't happen
那么我们将眼睁睁地看着自己被击败
well, then we're staring at defeat.
而这被击败的事实将 不应该不能够也不会被原谅
And that defeat should not and cannot and will not be forgiven.
这是一单很好的案子 对此我不会否认的
It was a good case I'm not denying that
但我需要信任我的人
but I need to trust my people.
除非你能许下承诺 不然的话我不可能...
Unless you can give your word, there's no way...
这不仅仅是公平的问题了
That's more than fair.
谢谢
Thanks.
但如果我做别的事情的话 对我来讲会更好
But it's better for me if I do something else.
警探
Detective.
跟你无关 是我自己的原因啦
It's not you, it's me.
- 但哪里... - 西区 我想
- But where... - The western, I think.
没错 西区感觉像家一样
yeah, Western feels like home.
你今天颇为表现了一番
You showed something today.
只是觉得要把这些话说出来
Just felt like it needed to be said.
听上去好象你在竞选什么呢
Sounds like you're running for something.
Eunetta
Eunetta.
好久没见
Been a while.
还以为你们这帮人在训练呢
Thought y'all was in training.
教练 你想我们明天几点到那儿呢?
So what time you want us to be there tomorrow, coach?
3点半到那儿就好
3:30 would be good.
- 希望你们到时全部来齐 - 好的
- Hope to see you all then. - A'right.
你们都他妈站那儿干嘛呢?
What the fuck y'all standing around for?
都给我做事去
Man, get to work.
...未能实现让我们的学校 给予孩子们一个未来的许诺
... to the false promise that our schools are providing a future for our children.
这就对了 就是这样
That's a seed.
对了
Yeah.
在这些案子当中...
In the cases...
被告Malik Carr 又名"Poot"...
of Malik Carr, a.k.a. "Poot"...
Herbert DeRodd Johnson 又名"Puddin" 以及Arthur Carroll...
Herbert DeRodd Johnson, a.k. A "Puddin'," Arthur Carroll...
你在这儿看到什么了?
What do you see right here?
一大堆废铁 每磅卖10美分
It's bulk metal. 10 cent a pound.
这里
Here.
铝
Aluminum.
你说得对 每磅卖30美分
Right you are. 30 cent a pound
没问题
no problem.
在这摩登时代
in these modern times
男人要留意盯着地上 找到什么就得捡起来 明白不?
a man gotta keep one eye on the ground pick up what he find, feel me?
如果你知道该往哪儿找 就有钱可赚
There's money to be made if you know where to look.
我希望你有在听着 因为我是在给你上课呢
I hope you listenin','cause I'm tryin'to school you here.
是啊 你不想知道
Yeah, you don't want to know.
你以为自己已经成熟了 可你还嫩着呢
You see, You think you brown, but you still green.
你好吗?
How ya doin'?
很有点看头哈?
That's somethin', huh?
就好象他们拿着一块大橡皮 横擦过去似的
It's like they took a big eraserand rubbed across it.
是啊
Yaeh
不过之前瘾君子跑到这儿来弄点玩意儿
Yeah, but before a dope fiend come down here cop a little somethin',
连鬼都不会找他的麻烦
ain't nary a soul hassle him.
混混们和警察 他们就让他那么着
Hoppers and police, they just let him be.
那样挺好的吧
Was a good thing, huh?
我只是说说而已
I'm just sayin'.
你大概不了解 我们的境遇惨着呢
You probly don't know, but it's rough out there, baby.
条子们回来对你推推搡搡的
Cops be back bangin'on you.
混混们跟你捣蛋
Hoppers be messin' with you.
是啊 谢谢你
yeah, Thank you.
哇靠
Aw, shit.
这儿有个十分硬币 可以拿来做种呢
That's a dime here. That's a seed.
跟上 小子
Come on, boy.